Guide to the Actors' Fund of America Records WAG.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series VIII: Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers Records, 1959-1980
  - Executive Board: Minutes, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter, 1977-1980 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Series IX: Oversize Items, 1891-1965
  - Actors’ Fund: Clippings, 1910-1926 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Actors’ Fund Events (Actors’ Fund Home, Anniversaries, Bread Basket Campaigns, and Annual Softball Game): Clippings, 1954-1961 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Actors’ Fund Events (Actors’ Fund Home, Anniversaries, Bread Basket Campaigns, and Annual Softball Game): Clippings, Press Releases, and Programs, 1956-1958 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (I), undated, 1892-1917 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (II), undated, 1910-1917 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: Clippings and Programs (partial) (III), undated, 1910-1917 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: Fair Topics and The Spectator (published for the Fair), 1892-1907 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: Friars Epistle (published for the Fair), 1917 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Actors’ Fund Fair: New York Dramatic Mirror: Clippings, 1891-1892 (Box 32, Folder 1a)
  - Actors’ Fund Founding and Actors’ Fund Home: Collages, 1900, 1902 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Actors' Fund Medal, 1970-1976 (Box 32, Folder 2a)
  - Actors’ Fund: Programs (partial), undated, 1915-1917 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Cohan, George M.: Memorial Resolution, Signed by AF Officers, Dec 1, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 3a)
  - Drawings (unidentified), undated (Box 24, Folder 3b)
  - Grand Opera: Programs (likely donated for Actors’ Fund Auctions), undated, 1902-1965 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - The Morning Telegraph: Portraits of Individuals who Made Contributions to the Actors' Fund Dime Bank, 1918 (Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - National Players: 40th Annual Tour (signed posters), 1988-1989 (Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Night of 100 Stars III: Letter to Alexander H. Cohen from Senator Frank Lautenberg, Eclosing Presentation Copy of his Remarks in the Senate, Jun 12, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 4a)
  - Theater Programs, 1891-1897, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Third Subscription Concert, Bath, New Assembly Rooms: Broadside (likely donated for Actors’ Fund Auctions), Dec 2, 1901 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Tomkins, Don: Wildcat Scrapbook: Clippings, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Series X: Scrapbooks and Unprocessed Material, 1875-2014
  - Subseries X:A: Hardcopy Scrapbooks, 1908-1973.
    - Actors’ Fund Benefits Clippings, 1961-1967 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Actors’ Fund General Clippings, 1962-1973 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Actors’ Fund Special Performances Clippings, 1967-1973 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Obituaries, Vol. I, 1913-May 3, 1918 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries, Vol. II, May 8, 1918-Jun 29, 1923 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Obituaries, Vol. III, Jun 29, 1923-Oct 8, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Obituaries, Vol. IV, Oct 19, 1927-Aug 1933 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Simon, Louis: Includes programs, press clippings, reviews, production photos, and original correspondence relating to theatre productions Simon worked on. Press materials also relate to the theatre scene. Subjects include Max Reinhardt, Lillian Gish, Ethel Barrymore, and picketing WPA personnel cuts. Correspondents include William Hollman, Marion Kohn, and Bide Dudley. Because Simon served as state director of the WPA Federal Theatre of New Jersey, a significant portion of programs, press and photos relate to WPA productions (1936-1937). These include “It Can’t Happen Here,” “The Trial of Dr. Beck,” “The Emperor’s New Clothes,” “Treasure Island,” and “The Adelphi Theatre.”, 1924-1940 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs, 1908-1913 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs, 1913-1917 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Theater Programs, 1916-1919 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Theater Programs, 1920-1921 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Theater Programs, 1932-1933 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Theater Programs (front and back cover of scrapbook), 1932-1933 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - USO: “Hellz-a-Poppin” Show: Includes journal reflections on travel and happenings behind the scenes of USO tour of army posts, arranged chronologically and by place. Also includes press reviews, and memorabilia such as postcards, travel brochures, and the army publications The Kelly Weekly and Beam: Hondo AAFNS Weekly, a military map of the “Strategic Middle Route” by the Union Pacific Railroad, cast and staff lists and autographs, and pages listing tour statistics. (I), 1942-1943, 1965, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - USO: “Hellz-a-Poppin” Show (II), 1942-1943, 1965, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - USO: “Hellz-a-Poppin” Show (photocopies of outer scrapbook binder), undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - USO: “Hellz-a-Poppin” Show (original outer binder), undated (Box 37)
  - Subseries X:B: Microfilmed Scrapbooks, 1900-1961.
    - Scrapbook 1 (Microfilm), 1900-1902 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 2 (Microfilm), 1910 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 3 (Microfilm), 1915-1918 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 4 (Microfilm), 1916-1918 (Reel 7822/1)
    - Scrapbook 5 (Microfilm), 1915-1928 (Box 7822/2)
    - Scrapbook 6 (Microfilm), 1922-1928 (Reel 7822/2)
    - Scrapbook 7 (Microfilm), 1925-1931 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 8 (Microfilm), 1926-1927 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 9 (Microfilm), 1941-1953 (Reel 7822/3)
    - Scrapbook 10 (Microfilm), 1942 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 11 (Microfilm), 1943-1947 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 12 (Microfilm), 1947-1953 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 13 (Microfilm), 1953-1957 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 14 (Microfilm), 1954-1958 (Reel 7822/4)
    - Scrapbook 15 (Microfilm), 1957-1961 (Reel 7822/4)
  - Subseries X:C: Unprocessed Material, 1875-2014.
    - Unprocessed Material, 2000s (Box 33)
    - Unprocessed Material, 2000s (Box 38)
    - George M. Cohan Dinner Phonograph Records (Fragile), 1938 (Box 39)
    - Arrangements of Funerals and Burials for Actor's Fund Members, undated (Box 49)
    - Annual Report Research Materials, circa 1990-1999 (Box 50)
    - Development Files, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Programs, Photographs and DVDs of Events and Benefits; Brochures; Miscellaneous Historical Materials, 1875-2014 (Box 52)
    - Oversized Historical Materials, 1900s-1960s (Box MSOS006)
      Scope and Content Note
      Includes early photographs of Joe Smith and Charles Dale, as well as a 1920s photograph of the Board of Trustees for The Actors Fund.
- Series XI: Aldrich Family Papers, circa 1850-1940
  - Scrapbooks, Photographs, Programs, and Publicity Materials, circa 1850-1940 (Box 41)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1850-1940 (Box 42-46)
  - Oversize Photographs, circa 1850-1940 (Box 47)
  - Actors' Fund Scrapbooks, circa 1850-1940 (Box 48)
- Series XII: Archived Website, Mar 29, 2009-ongoing
  The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund’s online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need. The website contains information on their services and programs, tickets to upcoming performances and events, and education and workshops.